DIEGO GARCÍA LOZANO

DATA SCIENTIST

CONTACT

+34 665215332

diegoglozano96@gmail.com

https://diegoglozano.netlify.app/

Madrid, Spain

SKILLS

Python/SQL/R

Pandas/Polars/Spark/sklearn/xgboost/ streamlit

Databricks/Linux

Communication and team work

EDUCATION

BSc Telecommunications engineering

Universidad de Oviedo

2014 - 2019

Mention in telematics

MSc Mathematical and computational engineering

UOC

2021 - Unfinished

Proffesional musician - Flute

Conservatorio de Oviedo

2009 - 2016

LANGUAGES

English - C1 by Cambridge

Native spanish

PROFILE

Versatile, fast learner, telecommunications engineer and Data Scientist with +5 years of experience. I have strong programming and business skills, and I have worked in many different projects and industries.

I have technical skills that cover many aspects: machine learning, statistics, NLP, data visualisation, models deployment, data engineering or arquitecture. Strong foundation in mathematics and very interested in other fields, like economy, business, experimentation or causal inference. Willingness to grow, and achieve new goals.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist

HP Inc 2022 - Now

- Working in a high impact global team that recommends best prices for almost all B2B HP deals in the world, earning ~10M\$ per year. Responsible for Europe (UK&I and eastern countries deployment) and China models
- Develop solutions for model monitoring (concept and data drift)
- Improvement of processes: migrating a local ETL to Databricks and rewriting to Spark with a decrease of ~90% of time
- Applying best practices in the team: implement the correct git flow and automation of processes
- Deployment of different apps in Linux machines to increase the adoption of our models among the stakeholders and minimize human errors
- Communication with other teams, like data engineers, MLOps, business teams...

Data Scientist

Endesa 2020-2022

- Working in the Advanced Analytics team, which is responsible for all data projects of the company
- · Worked for many business teams, like B2B, B2C or demand and prices
- B2B: credit risk / targeting marketing recommendations for potential clients
- B2C: sales. Understanding of clients churn in B2B2C based on mortality rates
- Demand and prices: buy / sell recommendation to B2B clients using Monte Carlo Markov Chain models

Data Scientist

Santander Bank

• Graph network (Twitter) and NLP for reputational risk

• Graph network (Twitter) and NEF for reputational ris

• Santander technology: IaC (Terraform)

Data Scientist

University of Oviedo

• Development of a classifier for income calls to the number 060 with NLP techniques, saving much money in the contact center

Full stack product developer

2024-Now

2019-2020

2019

- Developing a product from scratch to split a restaurant receipt with your friends
 - Infrastructure (linux)
 - o Computer vision / LLMs
 - o Data processing + databases
 - CI/CD (Dokku)
 - o Backend development (FastAPI) / Frontend development (ReactJS)
- You can access here: https://foodie-easypay.store we want your feedback!



